She was lost from the moment she saw him.
The French Lieutenant's Woman is a drama, romance,
history film directed by Karel Reisz.
In this story-within-a-story, Anna is an actress starring opposite Mike in a period piece
about the forbidden love between their respective characters, Sarah and Charles.
Both actors are involved in serious relationships, but the passionate nature
of the script leads to an off-camera love affair as well.
While attempting to maintain their composure and professionalism, Anna
and Mike struggle to come to terms with their infidelity.
Sarah / Anna, played by Meryl Streep.
Charles Henry Smithson / Mike, played by Jeremy Irons.
Sam, played by Hilton McRae.
Ernestina, played by Lynsey Baxter.
Mary, played by Emily Morgan.
Sonia, played by Penelope Wilton.
The French Lieutenant's Woman is a 1981 British romantic drama film directed by Karel
Reisz, produced by Leon Clore, and adapted by the playwright Harold Pinter.
It is based on The French Lieutenant's Woman, a 1969 novel by John Fowles.
The music score is by Carl Davis and the cinematography by Freddie Francis.
The film stars Meryl Streep and Jeremy Irons.
Other featured actors include Hilton McRae, Peter Vaughan, Colin Jeavons, Liz Smith, Patience
Collier, Richard Griffiths, David Warner, Alun Armstrong, Penelope Wilton, and Leo McKern.
The film received five Oscar nominations.
Streep was nominated for the Academy Award for Best Actress, and
Pinter for the Academy Award for Best Adapted Screenplay.
The film explores themes of adultery, based on novel
or book, lieutenant, love, tragedy.
The tone is emotional.